Sam Desborough

07709 426 551 | sam.desborough@gmail.com | github.com/desbo

Profile

An experienced full-stack developer with a broad range of technical and soft skills, currently working as a Senior Software Engineer in the Data Technology team at The Guardian.

Skills

Scala, Spark, JavaScript (ES6+, React, Redux, Webpack), AWS and Google Cloud. Mentoring and collaborating with fellow team members. Strong written and verbal communication, technical leadership and decision-making.

Experience

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, THE GUARDIAN OCT 2016 - PRESENT **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, THE GUARDIAN** JAN 2015 - OCT 2016

Developer on a number of teams including: Loyalty which focused on developing products to increase and maintain reader engagement on theguardian.com. Acquisitions, where the aim is to encourage readers to contribute financially and involved extensive work on A/B test deployment and analysis, building internal dashboards and dataflows. I'm currently working on the Data Technology team, building the infrastructure behind the Guardian's internal analysis tools and data lake using Spark, AWS EMR and Glue. I was also heavily involved in the Guardian's GDPR compliance implementation.

LEAD WEB DEVELOPER, DALTON MAAG FEB - DEC 2014

Lead developer for a brand new site for type foundry Dalton Maag. Introduced an agile workflow for the project and selected the technologies: MongoDB stores the site's content, exposed through a Node.js/Express-powered RESTful API to two AngularJS applications: a CMS and the public-facing site itself, which includes functionality to buy fonts hooked up to the Stripe payment gateway. Tests are written in Jasmine, with Supertest to target the API. I worked closely with inhouse design throughout the project and the site consumes an existing API that provides retail data. Wrote Ansible scripts to provision the application on Google Compute Engine VMs.

PHP DEVELOPER, KURT GEIGER APR 2013 - FEB 2014

Back-end developer for a range of Magento modules including a custom CMS used by the marketing team to maintain promotional content, Amazon MWS integration to synchronise products between Magento and amazon.com, and an equivalent system for selling on eBay. My testing experience enabled me to add Behat acceptance testing into the team's process.

QA ENGINEER, KURT GEIGER NOV 2011 - APR 2013

Lead tester for a redesign of kurtgeiger.com. My contributions to the team included Cucumber, for automated testing, introducing a feature branch-based git workflow to the team, and overseeing the launch of a new mobile site. Being a point of liaison with both product owners and developers has allowed me to gain a clear understanding of business requirements whilst ensuring the highest technical standards.

Education

ROADE SCHOOL, NORTHAMPTON 1996 - 2003

A-levels in Computing, English and Media Studies. GCSEs in Maths, English Language, English Literature, Science (double award), Computing with Business Studies, Geography, Media Studies, Drama, French, Electronics.